Brian Dudley

3640 Old Denton Road, Apt #505 Carrollton, TX 75007-7945 678-756-6863 bandrdudley@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/briandud1ey https://github.com/bandrdudley

Qualifications Summary

IT professional with over 12 years of experience in Networking and a Software Engineering. My development experience has been primarily focused on multi-tier distributed application, and web design / development. Specifically, my experience spans various stages of software development lifecycles such as requirements analysis, design, develop and test applications utilizing various languages and technologies. I have strong working knowledge in Java, GWT, Flex, Linux, Oracle, and various Web tools. I am a proven team player as well as an individual contributor.

Technical Qualifications

Languages & APIs: Java, jQuery/JavaScript, JSON, JSP, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, XML, PHP, SQL. Frameworks: Spring MVC, Google Web Toolkit (GWT), Adobe Flex (3.5), PureMVC Middleware: J2EE((EJB), JMS, Servlets), Jetty 8.1.2, Weblogic, Tomcat (4, 5.5, 6)

Operating Systems: Windows 7/XP, Windows 2000/NT, DOS, Unix, X windows.

Source Control: Git, Subversion, Subclipse, TortoiseSVN

Packages & Tools: Eclipse, Maven, Ant, Mockito, iRise, Flex Builder 3, Oracle SQL Developer 4.0 **Techniques:** OOP, OOD, MVP and MVC design patterns, Agile Software Development.

Databases: Oracle 12g, MySQL 5.0, SQLServer 7.0

Work Experience

AT&T Services, Inc., Richardson, TX Member of the Technical Staff

2008 - Current

Develop applications for the SalesExpress mobile application. Key responsibilities include:

- Develop User Interface utilizing HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript leveraging the Spring MVC framework, REST-based JSON web services and a Java / SQL backend
- Scripting with jQuery, jQueryUI and jQuery Mobile along with Handlebars.js to construct a Single Page Web application with Responsive Web Design
- Code mobile and desktop web applications using GWT, Adobe Flex, Java, EJB on Weblogic, Spring framework, JDO.
- Perform unit testing using JUnit, GWTTestCase, and Mockito testing framework increasing code coverage by 17% from the latest release

Izmocars (Prize Corporation), Chattanooga, TN Java Developer

2006 - 2008

Programmed, maintained and supported Automotive Customer Relationship Management (CRM) web application with Java Server Pages (JSP), Java, and Servlets.

- Constructed client-side browser code with open source AJAX libraries like Dojo and the Yahoo! User Interface Library (YUI). Debugged Javascript and Document Object Model (DOM) code with Firebug.
- Developed and implemented two projects for Internet Lead Management (ILM) screens allowing Internet Managers to manage complete sales cycle.
- Scripted enhanced Graphical User Interface (GUI) complete with fixed headers, and sortable columns utilizing Javascript and Cascading Style Sheets (CSS).
- Coded web services project using HTTP Digest Authentication and STAR format. Parsed XML documents with XPath to process automobile sales leads. Maintained message queue stored in MySQL database to manage inventory and service transactions.

The University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, University Relations, Chattanooga, TN 2005 - 2006 Student Web Developer

- Converted HTML web pages and created PHP pages using CSS and templates. Performed W3C web page validation to ensure XHTML 1.1 compliance.
- Edited graphics including JPG photographs and GIF logos with Photoshop 6.

Graduate Teaching & Research Assistant

- Provided lab assistance for Computer Networks course.
- Assisted writing curriculum for new Computer Security concentration.
- Maintained High Security Lab consisting of Windows XP, Debian Linux, BSD UNIX, Macintosh OS X clients.
- Worked with networking & forensics software such as Nessus, NeWT, SNORT, Forensic Toolkit, HexWorkshop, and EnCase.

The University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Center of Excellence for Computing Applications (CECA), Chattanooga, TN 2004 - 2005 Research Assistant

- Developed a Characticular and Chara
- Developed a Stereoviewer and StereoFunctions applications with C++ and OpenGL.
- Adapted an anaglyph program to display mathematical functions utilizing polarized stereo.
- Assisted with presentation of a Geowall 3D stereo rendering system for scientific visualization.

CORE, Inc., Portland, ME Network Analyst II

2000 - 2003

- Documented 1200 help desk tickets related to troubleshooting PC and software problems. Supported 50 VPN accounts and 30 AT&T dial up remote access accounts.
- Provided support for 12 Windows 2000 Advanced servers and 25 terminal servers including facilitating daily backups with Veritas.
- Created training manuals and systems documentation. Conducted weekly downloads via FTP. Trained end users in Office software and corporate systems.
- Maintained PC software images with Symantec Ghost.

Network Analyst I

- Connected over 250 end user workstations to Ethernet network and installed Norton Anti-Virus on these Windows 95/2000 systems.
- Installed peripherals such as printers, scanners, and switches. Configured and installed modems, network cards and RAM.

Education and Training

University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Chattanooga, TN Master of Science in Computer Science,

May, 2006

University of Southern Maine, Portland, ME
Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

December, 1993

Certifications & Coursework

Web Design Technician Certificate, Scarborough, ME, Northeast Technical Institute, 1999 Prepress Semester Certificate of Completion, Portland, ME, Imageset, Inc., 1999 Adobe Photoshop and Graphic Design I, Portland, ME, Maine College of Art, 1999 iRise Certified Modeler, Richardson, TX, AT&T Services, 2013

Honors & Awards

Upsilon Pi Epsilon member Honor Society in the Computing and Information Disciplines